<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ubuntu-planet | /james-random]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/blog/categories/ubuntu-planet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T10:32:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Gifford]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[james@jamesrgifford.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Ubuntu Hat Dash: Join Us!]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/askubuntu-hat-dash-join-us/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T10:26:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/askubuntu-hat-dash-join-us</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This year, as part of an attempt to spread holiday cheer,
Stack Exchange has decided to do a winter hat bash.</p>

<p>so, you might see something like this when you login to Ask Ubuntu today:</p>

<p><img src="http://i.stack.imgur.com/e4yeU.png" alt="enter image description here" /></p>

<p>So far, I've managed to earn the Gangnam style glasses, Guide my Sleigh, and Constantipolitan, for posting on meta.</p>

<p>Full list of hats is <a href="http://winterba.sh/">here</a> - I implore you, go forth and earn hats!
And if you dislike hats, there is an opt-out button - just click the "i hate hats" link, and you won't see any hats.</p>

<p>Just remember, hats are only around from now until Janurary 4th, so be quick!</p>

<p>Now hat Away! Hat Away! Hat Away All!</p>

<p><sub>cheesy I know.</sub></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Moved From Dropbox To Ubuntu One For Note Taking]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/dropbox-to-ubuntu-one-for-note-taking/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T18:46:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/dropbox-to-ubuntu-one-for-note-taking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, for those of you who know me, I'm pretty picky
about what I use for my syncing. And I have to be -
this is one of the more difficult parts of my electronic life,
and its even more difficult now.</p>

<p>Let's start with my requirements.</p>

<ul>
<li>free as in beer if at all possible. Hey, I'm cheap.</li>
<li>clients for the following OS's:

<ul>
<li>Ubuntu</li>
<li>Windows</li>
<li>iOS</li>
<li>Android. (I know, I need to clean up my operating system variety)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Some sort of folder structure, at least for the desktop.</li>
<li>Markdown is nice, but not required.</li>
</ul>


<p>Before I added Android to the mix, I had been using
PlainText and Dropbox. Worked wonderfully.
Now that I have an android device,
I'm moving to Ubuntu One notes, aka tomboy. Seems to work pretty well.</p>

<p>For Windows and Ubuntu clients, I'm using Tomboy.
For Android, I'm using <a href="https://launchpad.net/tomdroid">Tomdroid</a>,
and for iOS, I'm using a new one that doesn't work on iOS6 (yet!),
but should get fixed soon, called
<a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/webnotes-powered-by-ubuntu/id519580240?mt=8">webNotes (powered by Ubuntu One)</a>. All the platforms covered yay!</p>

<p>To get setup, I just installed Tomboy on my Ubuntu
and Windows computers.
I then installed the beta version of Tomdroid,
and connected everything to my Ubuntu One account.
Took about 20 minutes to do the switch, and was very painless!</p>

<p>So far, I've been using Ubuntu One in this fashion for about three months,
and it's going pretty well so far.</p>

<p>The ability to have my notes anywhere is great - and the fact it
integrates with a product made by one of my favorite companies (Canonical)
is even better!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RailsRumble 2012: A Beginners Postmortem]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/railsrumble2012-a-beginners-postmortem/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T18:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/railsrumble2012-a-beginners-postmortem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought I was a fairly competent and accomplished rails developer, for someone who was self taught, never had a job doing rails stuff, and who was young enough that a large part of the community is old enough be my dad.</p>

<p>And then I entered the Rails Rumble for 2012 with <a href="https://twitter.com/imnotanerd">@imnotanerd</a>, and spent a desperate 48 hours with my battling oauth, rails internals, Sinatra, cancan, and a Linux server.</p>

<p>At the end, I've got a few takeaways.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Come up with two ideas - one that only takes 12 hours to build, the other that takes the full 48.</p>

<p>This saved our bacon. We had two ideas - one was fairly complex. At 8PM Saturday I said "look. We've been banging our heads against this for almost 8 man hours. Time to start something else."</p>

<p>So I did a rails new, and thus Volla was born. Or reborn.</p></li>
<li><p>Git is your frenemy.</p>

<p>Git is a blessing and a curse. Commit early, often, push, deploy via Capistrano, repeat.</p>

<p>But make sure that your gitignore is properly updated.</p>

<p>Otherwise, you end up committing 20mb worth of binstubs. And your api keys. Not OK.</p>

<p>Anyway. Don't do that.</p></li>
<li><p>Stay on target...</p>

<p>Enough said. Don't get distracted by the cool matrix cat or something.</p></li>
<li><p>If you don't succeed, try again.
Take a month off, then try that idea again. I learned everything I know about rails because I said "I've got two weeks. Let's building something in 2 hours a day". (Side note: that's how I got sucked into Shoes/Hackety Hack, as well as delayed_paperclip. You devote time to something, you will fill it. Fact of life that I've discovered over the past 16 years I've been around on this planet.)</p></li>
<li><p>Leverage the knowledge of others.</p>

<p>I did the math, and between the two of us, we spent 8 hours man hours trying to figure out sessions in Sinatra. It was at this point I said "stop and move on, lets get this fixed". Time spent on authentication in rails? 20 minutes. (Authorization though, was closer to an hour, hour and a half)</p>

<p>The lesson to take away from this is that for almost everything you're doing, someone has invented that wheel already - so for the love of pete, USE IT. Thats the wonderful thing about a community.</p></li>
<li><p>If you don't know what adding $GEM to your gemfile will do, you probably don't want to do it.</p>

<p>I ran into this - had a gem, added it, broke everything. Removed, worked fine. (Not naming names here, it was some bad code I wrote elsewhere). But adding <em>one</em> gem was enough to break the whole app.</p></li>
<li><p>Use a logged chat.</p>

<p>We used skype - this worked, but the logs in skype are... well, less than wonderful. Part of this has to do with Skype for Linux, part of this has to do with Skype in general. If I had to do it again, I'd use Campfire, or even IRC.</p></li>
<li><p>Descriptive git commits.</p>

<p>"Fixed bugs" - If you're guilty of this, raise your hand! Oh look, everyones hand went up.</p>

<p>Don't. Do. This. Ever. Makes code review after the fact hard.</p></li>
<li><p>If you're confident, do some sort of TDD.</p>

<p>This would have cost us time, but saved us trouble. If we had automated testing in place, I would have known that we broke certain things with certain other changes. But... well, hindsight is 20-20.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Hopefully my tips here will be useful for people in the future. If not, oh well. I tried. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Ubuntu Cleanup Is now Underway]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/askubuntu-cleanup-underway/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-23T12:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/askubuntu-cleanup-underway</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>tl;dr: Head <a href="http://meta.askubuntu.com/questions/2651/ask-ubuntu-clean-up">over to meta</a>, read the post, <a href="http://meta.askubuntu.com/questions/257/how-does-ask-ubuntu-work">read the FAQ</a>, and start cleaning! :)</p>

<p>Anything further I might have to say would just be a copy-paste from the meta post, so please, go read that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Community Appreciation Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/community-appreciation-day/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T17:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/community-appreciation-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, for those of you that don't know, <a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/UCADay">Ubuntu Community Appreciation Day</a> is the first day that we set apart to say "Thank you" to all the various folks who help make the Ubuntu Community possible, and awesome.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, without furthur ado (whatever "ado" is!), I'll start the list of lists (in absolutely no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://castrojo.tumblr.com/">Jorge Castro</a> - it was Jorge who really got me kickstarted in the Ubuntu Community.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/maasj">Jason Maas</a>. While I haven't spoken (or even really communicated with him) in several years, this was the guy who introduced me to Ubuntu, so I have to thank him for that.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/wildbill">Bill Childers</a>. This guy taught me many tiny, newbie tricks, such as how to refresh the GRUB list (yeah, I didn't know how to do that until he showed me). He also wrote an awesome (somewhat outdated, but awesome) book I have read many, many times.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://philipballew.wordpress.com/">Philip Ballew</a>. He's awesome, if you've ever done anything with him, you'd know why. If you haven't, I suggest you get started.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://ubunturocking.wordpress.com/">Bilal Akhtar</a>. He's more of an inspiration than anything else, mainly because he's another young (he's 15, same as me) <a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Ubuntero">Ubuntero</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://akgraner.com/">Amber Graner</a>. She's done an awesome job of getting the <a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntuleadership">Ubuntu Leadership team</a> off the ground and to find it's place in the existing Ubuntu ecosystem. Thanks!</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://marcoceppi.com/">Marco Ceppi</a>. He's an awesome guy, one of the excellent team of Community moderators on Ask Ubuntu. Without him, I wouldn't spend (read: waste (in mom's eyes)) half as much time in the community helping people as I do.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>So, I'll leave you with this thought:</p>

<h3>Who do you appreciate in the community?</h3>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
