<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | /james-random]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-03T21:22:30-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Gifford]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[james@jamesrgifford.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleveland Ruby Hackibou for 3-11-2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/cleveland-ruby-hackibou-for-3-11-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-11T21:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jamesrgifford.com/cleveland-ruby-hackibou-for-3-11-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thursday night was interesting to say the least - I went to my first "Hackibou" - a place where coders in Cleveland area (I'm saying "Cleveland area" because I haven't found/heard of any non-Cleveland Hackibous) get together in a Coffee shop for an hour or two and work through some Ruby Code <!--more-->- we worked our way through the EdgeCase <a href="http://www.rubykoans.com/">Ruby Koans</a>, because the best way to learn how to code is to code. What happened was we (That is, <a href="http://jeffreygifford.com">Dad</a> and I) showed up at <a href="http://www.gypsybeans.com/">Gypsy Beans &amp; Baking Co</a>, ordered coffee, and found <a href="http://benwoz.com/">Ben Wozniki</a> at one of the tables, we sat down and started working on Ruby.
That night, we worked through the Koans as I mentioned above, and I also helped out Ray Jones of <a href="http://www.jumpstartinc.org/">JumpStart Inc</a>, as he was getting started in the Koans.
As I mentioned in a Tweet, it was a learning opportunity for both of us - Ray got started with the Koans (Which is a big thing, particularly since he didn't have any programming experience), I got to learn how to teach someone what things do and why they do them (Also learned that I was understanding something wrong - more on that if you want to read the GitHub commit messages from that night, or if you followed me on Twitter, you probably saw that) and I got to actually use <a href="http://macromates.com/">TextMate</a> for the first time. (Note: I still prefer vim over TextMate, for a number of reasons, the largest being that I don't have a Mac (Or the money to buy a TextMate license), with the others being that vi(m) is fast, and I can easily customize it. (NERDTree!).
Anyway, it was a fun night, and I look forward to the next Hackibou. If you're in the Cleveland Area and would like to have a crack at Ruby, take a look at the Meetup group <a href="http://www.meetup.com/ClevelandRuby/">here</a>, and I'll (probably) see you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
